ABHIJITH P

Full Stack Developer(MERN/MEAN)

📞 +91 7510720805 @ abhijithp327@gmail.com 🙋 www.linkedin.com/in/abhijith-p-64b13820a

❷ My Portfolio Link: https://abhijith-portfolio-omega.vercel.app/
❷ Pathanamthitta, Kerala

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 1+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer In Mern/Mean Gofreelab In Pvt. Ltd 01/2023 - Present Kochi, Kerala

- · Successfully converted whole project from Mern and Mean.
- Assist the Development Manager or the Senior Developer, as per the company's organisational structure, with programming/coding and software design.
- · Attend the company's development meetings and contribute with their programming knowledge.
- · Working on minor bug fixes.
- · Continuously improve their programming skills.
- · Gathering information from consumers about program functionality.
- · Monitoring the technical performance of internal systems.

Junior Software Developer In Mern/Mean(intern)
Expertzlab Technologies Pvt . Ltd 02/2022 - 12/2022 Kochi, Kerala

- · Successfully converted whole project from Mern and Mean.
- · Shadowing, mentoring, and training opportunities with experienced developers.
- Test software applications that the development team builds for efficiency and note any bugs.
- · Participate in code reviews with experienced web developers..

Junior Software Developer In Python (intern)
Technovalley Sofware India Pvt. Ltd 12/2021 - 01/2022

- Successfully converted whole project from Python
- · Shadowing, mentoring, and training opportunities with experienced developers.
- Test software applications that the development team builds for efficiency and note any bugs.
- · Participate in code reviews with experienced web developers.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Vns Arts And Science College 2018 - 2021 Konni , Kerala

CERTIFICATES

FULL STACK DEVELOPER IN PYTHON TECHNOVALLEY Kochi, Kerala

MERN/MEAN STACK DEVELOPER EXPERTLAB Kochi, Kerala

GOFREELAB
CERIFICATE IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Ecommerce Website With Admin Panel With MERN

- An ecommerce store built with MERN stack, and utilizes third party API's. This ecommerce store enable three main different flows or implementations
- Buyers browse the store categories, products and brands
- Sellers or Merchants manage their own brand component
- Admins manage and control the entire store components
- · features:
 - Node provides the backend environment for this application
 - Express middleware is used to handle requests, routes
 - Mongoose schemas to model the application data
 - React for displaying UI components
 - Redux to manage application's state
 - Redux Thunk middleware to handle asynchronous redux actions

Project Git Hub Link:

https://github.com/abhijithp327/Ecommerce-Admin-Website

Edu Learn Course Website Fully Responsive

- MERN stack-based project, we'll develop an e-learning course catalog website. You'll display the list of all the courses on the website. The website will also allow users to search the available courses with a search bar.
 •With Css Media Queries Responsive
- Express framework on Node.js to develop the backend API, which will interact with the MongoDB database where the data is fetched from and stored. After setting up the backend, we'll implement the front-end components and add search functionality. onal components.

Project Git Hub Link:

https://github.com/abhijithp327/A-Course-Website-UI

Portfolio With React Vite Fully Responsive

- Portfolio is a collection of your best projects, showcasing your abilities in building websites.
- Completly responsive with media query

Project Git Hub Link:

https://github.com/abhijithp327/Portfolio

SKILLS

Tools

React • Node • Mongodb • Css3 • Vite • Nextjs •

Angular